# Bhawna Agarwal

Product Designer with 6 years of formal design education, and 8+ years of experience designing and shipping well-crafted, high-impact experiences in the industry. I specialize in applying product thinking to break down complex problems and craft helpful experiences.

# **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

## Product Designer, Microsoft

April 2023-Present, Full-time | San Francisco Bay Area

- Leading design for the Amplify Intelligence team, leveraging AI to reimagine help and support experiences
- Nurturing team growth by refining design processes, presenting impactful case studies, and collaborating with senior leadership to strengthen design culture

## Senior Product Designer, Wish

January 2021-April 2023, Full-time | San Francisco

- Led design for Shopping Cart, Checkout, and Payments. Redesigned the experience which led to a -21.8% decline in the order refund rate.
- Influenced peers and executive leadership to prioritize user needs, driving alignment on key design decisions.
- Contributed to Wish's design system, improving consistency and scalability

#### **UX** Designer, Microsoft

April 2018-July 2019, Full-time | Hyderabad, India

- Sole designer responsible for Azure Backup, drove UX strategy and execution
- Partnered with 10+ product managers across multiple projects to enhance the Azure Backup service

#### UX Design Lead | Reported to CEO, Postman API Platform

June 2016-December 2017, Full-time | Bangalore, India

- Led UX strategy and execution as the sole designer, delivering 6+ core projects in one year, driving productivity gains for 15M+ developers
- Proposed and secured executive buy-in for a more usable, extensible Data Editor component - a complex component in Postman's design system. Led the design process, ensuring seamless integration into the design system.
- Wore multiple hats beyond design—conducted research, provided customer support, authored product copy, and wrote feature marketing blog posts

#### **Earlier experiences**

- UX Designer, Housing.com, Full-time | June-December 2015
- UX Design Intern, HCII, Carnegie Mellon University | May-July 2014
- UX Design Intern, Robert Bosch | May-July 2013

# **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Masters in UX Design

IIT Guwahati, India

Bachelor of Design with Minor in Computer Science

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Publications in ACM digital library as first author
- First position in OzCHI 2014 –
  International student design challenge
- S.N. Bose Scholar

#### **SKILLS**

UX Research	Software
and Design	Figma
Contexual Inquiry	Sketch
User Interviews	Principle
Persona Building	Invision
Writing Job Stories	Photoshop
Info. Architecture	Illustrator
Heuristic Evaluation	InDesign
<b>Usability Testing</b>	Tableau
Wireframing	
Mobile Design	Coding
Visual/UI Design	HTML/ CSS
Prototyping	Javascript
UX Writing	jQuery
Storytelling	Python

# **PORTFOLIO**

bhawna2109.github.io/design